#### RESUME

# RAFAEL JORGE CACERES

## Python Developer





ing\_jorge\_caceres@hotmail.com



https://github.com/EJ001-DEV/BotsProject.git

#### **SUMMARY:**

With more than eighteen (18) years of experience in software development. High domain in analysis, testing, programming and implementation of systems through the software life cycle and applying the best methods to deliver quality software to the new and existing customers.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

#### **InterSistemas**

- 2020-Now
- 9 Dominican Republic
- Created tools to improve process in a supermarket that sell a product manually, now the process sell is with a new software, a manually sell was made in 5 minutes then with this software can be made in 30 seconds.
- Improved inventory control with a loss of products around RD\$7,000 per month to RD\$0.00 with automatics tips of buys, measurements and control of expiration date.
- Manager Health Risk Salud Segura (currently closed)

(Jonny Herrera Project Manager: +1809-330-3187)

- 2014-2020 (**6 years**)
- ♥ Dominican Republic
- Manage to re-engineering process and implementing the ERP software and reduce the time into the cycle-life of health claims authorization from clinics and hospitals of one month to four days.
- Development of a tool for the administration of health claims reduction of 80% of scams related to clinics or doctors to 0% settlement of health claims.
- 15% increase in affiliates after implementing management tools and massive uploads of affiliates obtained from husiness visits
- Reduction of accounting closing time from a week and a half to one day.
- Implementation of search tools and correction of accounting imbalances.
- Reduced waste of paper with the module of group health claims authorization of 70 pages per claims to 1 page that is the final authorization to pay the clinic or hospital.
- Manager Health Risk Monumental

(contact Project Manager: +1829-232-1766)

- **2005-2011 (6 years)** ♥ Dominican Republic
- Be part of the staff to program and implement of the system ERP "GestionARS" on a passed time of 4 month and finished successfully all the test with the government institution.
- Increase in 80% health debt collections from companies after creating a CRM.

#### STRENGTHS:

Creativity to solve problems.



self-taught person to learn new technologies.



Driven staff through implementing software.



Polite and professional communication with clients.

#### **SKILLS:**

- Python
- Django
- React

- Oracle Forms
- HTML
- CSS
- С
- Databases:
- Oracle
- PostgreSQL
- Proved skills in analysis, design and programming under detailed specifications.
- and Linux environment, expertise on Network, Computer repair, MS Office, Knowledge in backup and data recovery, CASE tools.

#### **EDUCATION:**

Technological University Santiago (UTESA) 809-582-7156 Engineer in Computer Science.

ADDITIONAL SECTION:

#### ( 2002 - 2007 )

Language: English / Spanish. English skills:

Speak Write Read Listen

# RESUME RAFAEL JORGE CACERES

Python Developer

Dominican Republic, Santiago de los Caballeros +1(829) 427-7211

ing

ing\_jorge\_caceres@hotmail.com

()

https://github.com/EJ001-DEV/BotsProject.git



### UNIVERSIDAD TECNOLOGICA DE SANTIAGO

OTESA

Fundada el 12 de noviembre de 1974 en Santiago de los Caballeros, República Dominicana

# LA FACULTAD DE Arquitectura e Ingeniería CONFIERE EL TITULO DE

Ingeniero en Informática

# A Rafael Eduardo Jorge Cáceres

Tomando en cuenta que ha cursado y aprobado satisfactoriamente sus estudios y cumplido con todos los requisitos legales y académicos de acuerdo con las leyes dominicanas y con los estatutos y reglamentos de la universidad.

En testimonio de ello, le expide el presente Titulo que refrenda con las firmas y los sellos correspondientes, en Santiago de los Caballeros, República Dominicana, a los 14 días del mes de Abril del año 2007.

Registrado bajo el No. 21721 Folio 113 del libro de grados y títulos No. 5